<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Terminal on integralist</title>
    <link>http://www.integralist.co.uk/tags/terminal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Terminal on integralist</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 13:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.integralist.co.uk/tags/terminal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Terminal Password Manager</title>
      <link>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/terminal-password-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/terminal-password-manager/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Installation Example Usage Exporting Data Synchronisation Mobile and GUI Applications MultiFactor Authentication Conclusion  
Introduction I&amp;rsquo;m guessing that you have an app like 1Password or KeePassX to manage your passwords and other login credentials and you&amp;rsquo;re now looking for a cheaper alternative, and also one that doesn&amp;rsquo;t rely on a GUI (although as you&amp;rsquo;ll see that&amp;rsquo;s still possible).
If so, then &amp;ldquo;Pass&amp;rdquo; might be something of interest to you as it offers you the ability to securely store information via the command line interface (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terminal Debugging Utilities</title>
      <link>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/terminal-debugging-utilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/terminal-debugging-utilities/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Prerequisites  TCP and HTTP OSI Model  Utilities  top: check running processes for cpu and memory utilisation ps: see what processes are running strace: monitor interactions between processes lsof: list of open files netstat: monitoring network traffic ifconfig: configure or review your network interfaces iftop: monitors network traffic and displays table of bandwidth usage iptraf: monitoring network traffic (more visual than netstat, not as detailed) tcpdump: network packet sniffer wireshark: network packet sniffer and analyser (gui) tshark: network packet sniffer and analyser telnet: utility for communicating with another host  Honorable mentions Conclusion</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>