<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Performance on integralist</title>
    <link>http://www.integralist.co.uk/tags/performance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Performance on integralist</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 09:32:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.integralist.co.uk/tags/performance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistics and Graphs: The Basics</title>
      <link>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/statistic-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 09:32:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/statistic-basics/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Information vs Data Watch out for misleading data Frequency Pie Chart Bar Chart  Stacked Split  Histograms  Differences? Calculating dimensions Frequency Density?  Line Graphs  
Introduction I started learning about statistics because I found myself doing a lot of operational monitoring (i.e. making systems more observable, instrumenting individual services, and monitoring that data via custom built dashboards).
Although, for the most part, everything worked as expected and I generally understood the data I was seeing visualised, I wanted to be sure I wasn&amp;rsquo;t missing any important information (or worse, mis-representing the data).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NSQ Queue Reader Best Practices</title>
      <link>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/queue-reader-best-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/queue-reader-best-practices/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Ephemeral Channels? Fail quickly Verify your message handling logic Be wary of global variables Instrument timers around your primary message handler Pynsq doesn’t support coroutines Prevent messages backing up in the queue Avoid API libraries auto-retrying expensive operations Place blocking IO operations into a thread pool Rate limit yourself Disable yourself Drop or Requeue?  
Introduction This post should serve as a guide for best practices when dealing with services that consume messages from queues and process those messages (we refer to them as QRs or &amp;lsquo;Queue Readers&amp;rsquo;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Load Testing Guidelines</title>
      <link>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/load-testing-guidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/load-testing-guidelines/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Use real datasets Identify collateral damage Stub services if necessary Distribute your traffic Automate for reproducible runs Consider disabling authentication Don&amp;rsquo;t immediately scale dependencies Send traffic from different geographical regions Decide if your tool should support reusing connections Start testing a single instance, before moving onto clusters Verify load using multiple strategies Reset your environment between test runs Document the results Tools  
Introduction This post should serve as a guideline for running load tests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTTP/2</title>
      <link>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/http2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/http2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Persistent Connections Multiplexing Compression Prioritization SSL/TLS Server Push Implementations  Nginx Go  References  
Introduction This is a super quick post for demonstrating how to utilise the new HTTP/2 protocol. If you&amp;rsquo;re unfamiliar with it, then let me spend a brief few moments discussing some of the highlights:
 Single, persistent connection Multiplexing Header compression Prioritization Encryption Server Push  If none of these features make sense, then allow me to clarify further&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>