<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Guide on integralist</title>
    <link>http://www.integralist.co.uk/categories/guide/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Guide on integralist</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 13:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.integralist.co.uk/categories/guide/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Concepts From the C Programming Language</title>
      <link>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/concepts-from-the-c-programming-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/concepts-from-the-c-programming-language/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Compilation  Compilers C11 safe functions  Hello World Constants vs Directives Quotations Char Type Null Terminator Pointers Arrays Enumerators Memory Allocation with different Types Reallocating Memory Function Prototypes Conclusion  
Introduction I decided recently to read a book on the C programming language. The idea was to learn some more low-level concepts that other higher-level languages were abstracting away from me.
This write up is the result of some of those learnings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Man Pages</title>
      <link>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/understanding-man-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2016 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/understanding-man-pages/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Sections Sub sections Accessing different sections  
Introduction Your operating system provides manual pages that explain what specific commands do and where they can be located on your computer.
Most of us are at least familiar with opening a terminal and typing:
man &amp;lt;some_command&amp;gt;  But you might be confused, when you see a manual page informing you to check out &amp;lt;another_command&amp;gt;(2). For example, you might be shown the message at the end of a man page that says See also: chmod(2).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syscalls and C</title>
      <link>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/syscalls-and-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/syscalls-and-c/</guid>
      <description>Syscalls and C This post is aimed at explaining the difference between a system call (provided by the Linux kernal) and a wrapper function that has a similar name within one of the C standard libraries.
I have no formal Computer Science (CS) background, I started programming in 1999 and only from 2016 am I starting to learn the C programming language in order to help give me a deeper knowledge of how *nix systems work and other core CS concepts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bits and Bytes</title>
      <link>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/bits-and-bytes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/bits-and-bytes/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Bit Byte RAM Bit and RAM Visualisation Bits and Numbers IPs Base Numbers  Convert Base-10 into Base-2&amp;frasl;8 Convert Base-10 into Base-16 Convert Any Base to Base-10  CIDR Conclusion  
Introduction So this is a bit of a random journey through some different computer based subjects. Things that I felt I should try to better understand. Some of it will be very basic, but hopefully it&amp;rsquo;ll be useful to those who are new to tech, and are interested in learning these things (or old dogs like me who should know better).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terminal Password Manager</title>
      <link>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/terminal-password-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/terminal-password-manager/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Installation Example Usage Exporting Data Synchronisation Mobile and GUI Applications MultiFactor Authentication Conclusion  
Introduction I&amp;rsquo;m guessing that you have an app like 1Password or KeePassX to manage your passwords and other login credentials and you&amp;rsquo;re now looking for a cheaper alternative, and also one that doesn&amp;rsquo;t rely on a GUI (although as you&amp;rsquo;ll see that&amp;rsquo;s still possible).
If so, then &amp;ldquo;Pass&amp;rdquo; might be something of interest to you as it offers you the ability to securely store information via the command line interface (e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>