<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Patterns on integralist</title>
    <link>http://www.integralist.co.uk/tags/patterns/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Patterns on integralist</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2015 13:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.integralist.co.uk/tags/patterns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing for Simplicity</title>
      <link>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/designing-for-simplicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2015 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/designing-for-simplicity/</guid>
      <description>This post was originally written for David Walsh back in 2015. I&amp;rsquo;ve since decided to reproduce it here for my own records - Integralist: August, 2017.
 Before we get started, it&amp;rsquo;s worth me spending a brief moment introducing myself to you. My name is Mark (or @integralist if Twitter happens to be your communication tool of choice) and I currently work for BBC News in London England as a principal engineer/tech lead; and I&amp;rsquo;m also the author of &amp;ldquo;Pro Vim&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MVCP: Model, View, Controller, Presenter</title>
      <link>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/mvcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2013 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/mvcp/</guid>
      <description>Introduction  Model View Controller  Mixed definitions  God Controller Problems Skinny Controller  Presenters?  What problem are Presenters trying to solve? How do they work?  Code Example  Controller View Presenter  Conclusion  
Introduction Model, View, Controller (MVC). This is a pretty standard architectural pattern and has been in use when developing software since the early 1970&amp;rsquo;s.
The basic principle of the pattern is to separate the different areas of logic from your application into distinct compartments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Message Passing in Object Oriented Code</title>
      <link>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/message-passing-in-object-oriented-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/message-passing-in-object-oriented-code/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Quick example The Proxy Design Pattern How Ruby handles method calls Implementing method_missing Conclusion  
Introduction In my previous post I quoted the following description of object-oriented design…
 Object-Oriented Design is about the messages that get sent between objects and not the objects themselves.
 The reason I felt this quote was important for good code design was because it helped focus our attention on improving our object&amp;rsquo;s interfaces.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>