<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker on integralist</title>
    <link>http://www.integralist.co.uk/tags/docker/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker on integralist</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 13:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.integralist.co.uk/tags/docker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Environments Within Docker Containers</title>
      <link>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/dev-environments-within-docker-containers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/dev-environments-within-docker-containers/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Python Go Mounting Volumes  
Introduction You&amp;rsquo;re a software engineer with a new laptop.
You&amp;rsquo;re going to be writing code in multiple languages.
You&amp;rsquo;re going to have projects of varying dependencies.
But you want to avoid the issues you&amp;rsquo;ve had in the past:
 Messy installations of lots of different software packages. Clogging up your system with programming language version managers.  You decide to use Docker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Client Cert Authentication</title>
      <link>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/client-cert-authentication/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2015 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/client-cert-authentication/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Directory Structure Configuration Building Running Verifying Revocation References Conclusion  
Introduction The purpose of this post is to demonstrate how to configure nginx to use client certificates for authenticated access to your back-end service (in this example: a Ruby/Sinatra application).
 Note: the focus of this post isn&amp;rsquo;t about Ruby/Sinatra so don&amp;rsquo;t worry if your back-end service is built with another programming language
 I won&amp;rsquo;t be going into the details of how most of it was set-up, as the majority of this was already documented in a previous blog post here: Setting up nginx with Docker so I recommend reading through that first if you&amp;rsquo;re new to Docker and nginx.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up Nginx With Docker</title>
      <link>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/setting-up-nginx-with-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/setting-up-nginx-with-docker/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Just give me the code Setting up nginx Setting up the Ruby application Linking your app to nginx Conclusion  
Introduction I wanted to learn about how to use the popular proxy server nginx for handling &amp;ldquo;reverse proxy&amp;rdquo; duties on a Ruby project I was working on. So I decided the easiest thing to do in order to play around with nginx (as I work on a MacBook Pro laptop), would be to install and run it (and my back-end application) within Docker containers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing for Simplicity</title>
      <link>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/designing-for-simplicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2015 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/designing-for-simplicity/</guid>
      <description>This post was originally written for David Walsh back in 2015. I&amp;rsquo;ve since decided to reproduce it here for my own records - Integralist: August, 2017.
 Before we get started, it&amp;rsquo;s worth me spending a brief moment introducing myself to you. My name is Mark (or @integralist if Twitter happens to be your communication tool of choice) and I currently work for BBC News in London England as a principal engineer/tech lead; and I&amp;rsquo;m also the author of &amp;ldquo;Pro Vim&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>