<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gpg on integralist</title>
    <link>http://www.integralist.co.uk/tags/gpg/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gpg on integralist</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 08:33:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.integralist.co.uk/tags/gpg/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hashing, Encryption and Encoding</title>
      <link>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/hashing-and-encryption/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 08:33:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/hashing-and-encryption/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I&amp;rsquo;ve written previously (and in-depth) on the subject of security basics, using tools such as GPG, OpenSSH, OpenSSL, and Keybase. But this time I wanted to focus in on the differences between encryption and hashing, whilst also providing a slightly more concise reference point for those already familiar with these concepts.
Before we get started, let&amp;rsquo;s see what we&amp;rsquo;ll be covering:
 Terminology Hashing vs Encryption MAC vs HMAC Base64 Encoding Random Password Generation Hash Functions  shasum hashlib cksum  OpenSSH OpenSSL  Generating a key pair Encrypting and Decrypting Randomness  GPG  Generating a key pair Automate Asymmetrical Encryption and Decryption Symmetrical Encryption and Decryption Signing keys Signing encrypted files  Keybase</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Key Architecture</title>
      <link>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/key-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/key-architecture/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Visual Breakdown Vulnerabilities? Conclusion  
Introduction Just a quick post to cover the key architecture I&amp;rsquo;m using currently. I&amp;rsquo;m very interested to know how others are doing things in the hope that I can improve the security of my setup.
 Note: I&amp;rsquo;m not a security paranoia nut, so I&amp;rsquo;m not looking for the most concrete solution. But definitely want to be sure I&amp;rsquo;m not missing anything obvious either</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security basics with GPG, OpenSSH, OpenSSL and Keybase</title>
      <link>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/security-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/security-basics/</guid>
      <description>Introduction What are keys and how do they work? Understanding PKI OpenSSL vs OpenSSH What is GPG? Creating your own keys  OpenSSH OpenSSL GPG  Multiple Keys?   How to encrypt data using GPG, OpenSSL and Keybase  GPG encryption  Asymmetrical encryption Symmetrical encryption Key Signing Digital Signatures Revoking Keys  OpenSSL encryption Keybase Which should I use?  Creating, self-signing, issuing and revoking certificates Conclusion   UPDATE: for those short on time, read the following Introduction, What are keys and how do they work?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>