<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on integralist</title>
    <link>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on integralist</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 13:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Environments Within Docker Containers</title>
      <link>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/dev-environments-within-docker-containers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/dev-environments-within-docker-containers/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Python Go Mounting Volumes  
Introduction You&amp;rsquo;re a software engineer with a new laptop.
You&amp;rsquo;re going to be writing code in multiple languages.
You&amp;rsquo;re going to have projects of varying dependencies.
But you want to avoid the issues you&amp;rsquo;ve had in the past:
 Messy installations of lots of different software packages. Clogging up your system with programming language version managers.  You decide to use Docker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Key Architecture</title>
      <link>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/key-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/key-architecture/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Visual Breakdown Vulnerabilities? Conclusion  
Introduction Just a quick post to cover the key architecture I&amp;rsquo;m using currently. I&amp;rsquo;m very interested to know how others are doing things in the hope that I can improve the security of my setup.
 Note: I&amp;rsquo;m not a security paranoia nut, so I&amp;rsquo;m not looking for the most concrete solution. But definitely want to be sure I&amp;rsquo;m not missing anything obvious either</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hitchikers Guide to Go</title>
      <link>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/hitchikers-guide-to-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/hitchikers-guide-to-go/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Private Repo Access Build and Compilation Dependency Information Dependency Management Documentation Testing Logging Godo Import Race Conditions New vs Make Custom Types Function Types Enumerator IOTA Struct: Var vs Type Embedded Structs Reference vs Value See all methods on &amp;lt;Type&amp;gt; Convert Struct into JSON Pretty Printing JSON String Convert Struct into YAML Sorting Structs Read Users Input HTTP Middleware Sessions HTTPS TLS Request HTTP GET Web Page Custom HTTP Request Methods Pointers Type Assertion Line Counting Reading File in Chunks Time Starting and Stopping things with Channels Channel Pipelines Templating Error handling Socket Programming Comparing Maps Zip File Contents Shell Commands New Instance Idiom JSON Connection Draining</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concepts From the C Programming Language</title>
      <link>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/concepts-from-the-c-programming-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/concepts-from-the-c-programming-language/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Compilation  Compilers C11 safe functions  Hello World Constants vs Directives Quotations Char Type Null Terminator Pointers Arrays Enumerators Memory Allocation with different Types Reallocating Memory Function Prototypes Conclusion  
Introduction I decided recently to read a book on the C programming language. The idea was to learn some more low-level concepts that other higher-level languages were abstracting away from me.
This write up is the result of some of those learnings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple SSH Keys for Different GitHub Accounts</title>
      <link>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/multiple-ssh-keys-for-different-github-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/multiple-ssh-keys-for-different-github-accounts/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The Problem? The Solution Creating a new Key SSH Config Optional Shell Function Alternatives? Another Alternative  
Introduction I recently had an issue with my GitHub set-up which has since prompted me to write this post. The issue I had was dealing with multiple GitHub accounts via SSH on a single laptop.
So I have a GitHub account under the username Integralist. This is a personal account, and up until recently I was also using it to access my work&amp;rsquo;s private repos (BBC and BBC-News).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>