<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Development on integralist</title>
    <link>http://www.integralist.co.uk/categories/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Development on integralist</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 13:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.integralist.co.uk/categories/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Environments Within Docker Containers</title>
      <link>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/dev-environments-within-docker-containers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/dev-environments-within-docker-containers/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Python Go Mounting Volumes  
Introduction You&amp;rsquo;re a software engineer with a new laptop.
You&amp;rsquo;re going to be writing code in multiple languages.
You&amp;rsquo;re going to have projects of varying dependencies.
But you want to avoid the issues you&amp;rsquo;ve had in the past:
 Messy installations of lots of different software packages. Clogging up your system with programming language version managers.  You decide to use Docker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple SSH Keys for Different GitHub Accounts</title>
      <link>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/multiple-ssh-keys-for-different-github-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/multiple-ssh-keys-for-different-github-accounts/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The Problem? The Solution Creating a new Key SSH Config Optional Shell Function Alternatives? Another Alternative  
Introduction I recently had an issue with my GitHub set-up which has since prompted me to write this post. The issue I had was dealing with multiple GitHub accounts via SSH on a single laptop.
So I have a GitHub account under the username Integralist. This is a personal account, and up until recently I was also using it to access my work&amp;rsquo;s private repos (BBC and BBC-News).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up Nginx With Docker</title>
      <link>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/setting-up-nginx-with-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.integralist.co.uk/posts/setting-up-nginx-with-docker/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Just give me the code Setting up nginx Setting up the Ruby application Linking your app to nginx Conclusion  
Introduction I wanted to learn about how to use the popular proxy server nginx for handling &amp;ldquo;reverse proxy&amp;rdquo; duties on a Ruby project I was working on. So I decided the easiest thing to do in order to play around with nginx (as I work on a MacBook Pro laptop), would be to install and run it (and my back-end application) within Docker containers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>